Guide to the Oregon State University Military Photographs Collection 1875-1975
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- Inter War Years, 1919-1939; Series III
  - OAC Field Artillery Battalion, circa 1920
    - Artillery caissons parked by Armory, circa 1920; P002:584; 1.0 3 x 5 prints; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photo shows the Artillery Battalion's caissons and limbers lined up for inspection on the side field of the Armory (Mc Alexander Field House) Good detail of building side entrance during the 1920s.
    - Horse-drawn caissons/limbers on campus #2, circa 1920; P002:586; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Side view of horse-drawn limber with trailing caisson moving on campus
    - Horse-drawn artillery caissons/limbers on campus, circa 1920; P002:587; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Movement of artillery caissons/limbers through campus
    - Horse-drawn artillery caissons/limbers on parade, circa 1920; P002:588; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This photo shows four horse teams attached to limbers/caissons moving through campus.
    - Horse-drawn caisson with limbers in line on parade field, circa 1920; P002:599; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Line up of horse-drawn caissons with limbers on parade field, probably on inspection day. At right of photograph is a mock pillbox and barricade for inspection day military demonstrations.
    - Artillery tractor and 155mm Howitzer and cadet formation, circa 1920; P002:604; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photograph shows the M1918 155mm Heavy Artillery being pulled by the caterpillar tractor by Mc Alexander Armory. The large cannon received the name "Aggie Boy" which was painted on its barrel. Column of cadets marching beside artillery are armed with holstered pistols. Motor Transport Corps motorcycle on right with sidecar.
    - Horse Drawn artillery pieces moving through campus, circa 1920; P002:624; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This photograph shows a column of artillery pieces (75mm) being moved through campus. Probably both companies of artillery during training all being moved.
    - Horse-drawn caisson with limber on parade field, circa 1920; P002:626; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This photograph depicts a parade of horse drawn limbers and caissons on parade field. The weapons are not present in this formation. Photo is probably of the early 1920 vintage, as with others in this group highlighting the new unit on OAC.
    - Horseback cadets with artillery in background, circa 1920; P002:629; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Three horseback cadets by Armory with artillery in background. Photos are of the era after WWI with brimmed Pattern 1912 Service Caps and high collar tunics. The Mc Alexander Field House (then Armory) is in background. Clear photo of uniforms and horse equipment. The artillery unit was formed after WWI using surplus equipment, a number of photos in this group include artillery in content.
    - French 75mm cannons with caissons by Armory, circa 1920; P002:654; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photograph shows the French 75mm with their caissons lined up for inspection day
    - French 75mm Artillery Cadets firing gun, circa 1920; P002:655; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Detailed photograph of cadets firing artillery on open range (Probably Yakima area) The four man crew in action shows loading a shell into the gun with a cadet sitting on the framework at left. To the rear of the gun, the caisson with ammunition and supplies can be seen open and ready for action. Reverse of photograph is stamped with a Oregon State University Archives mark and the remains of an order form from the photo engravers company. Of special note is a small strip of a campus photograph. 1x4.5 inches pasted to reverse. Education Building on left with Benton Hall obscured by trees on right.
    - Heavy artillery on OAC Campus after WWI, circa 1920; P002:657; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This excellent photo shows the "Aggie Boy" M1918 155mm Heavy gun being towed by the Caterpillar tractor in standard use during the period. The gun is followed by a heavy truck for supplies and ammunition. Also if note is the WWI era motor cycle with sidecar and a cadet sitting watching the parade. Great detail in shot of the "latest" equipment assigned to the new artillery training battalion on OAC beginning just after WWI. The heavy truck following is the "4WD truck" that was manufactured by Four Wheel Drive Co. in Clintonville, WI A WWI vintage US Army truck.
    - French 75mm Artillery piece with caisson by Armory, circa 1920; P002:659; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A highly detailed photo of one of the Artillery Battalion French 75mm cannons with it's caisson in the field next to the Armory. Vehicles in background include a small sporty Ford Model T "Speedster" by the Armory entrance. The artillery piece is shown in clear detail with the fittings and straps of the caisson also rendered well.
    - Heavy artillery, affectionately known as "Aggie Boy", circa 1920; P002:660; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Aggie Boy was the name given to the heavy artillery training piece assigned to OAC in the 1920s. This is detailed view of the M1918 155mm Howitzer, a French design from WWI. Cadet leaning on gun carriage at right. The west side of the Armory (Mc Alexander Field House) in background. "Aggie Boy" has been hand painted in black on the barrel of the artillery piece.
    - Horse-drawn artillery moving by Armory, circa 1920; P002:661; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Six horse teams are shown pulling caissons and French 75mm artillery pieces on campus to the west of Armory.
    - OAC Cadets demonstrating on French 75mm cannon, circa 1920; P002:663; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photo depicts a crew of cadets working with the French 75mm cannon on campus. Uniforms are of WWI vintage, artillery cadets were still wearing the campaign hats and wrapped puttees. Caisson is open showing stowage of ammunition and supplies. Good, clear detail of uniforms and equipment.
    - Artillery pieces being stored in Armory, children involved, circa 1920; P002:664; 2.0 3 x 5 prints; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This photo shows a line of caissons and 75mm Field guns being stored inside the Armory (Mc Alexander Field House). Of special note are the young children in photo. 2 officers/NCOs are riding on one of the caissons, and there are 6 children (Pre teen) involved with the event.
    - M1918 155mm Howitzer, view of bore, circa 1920; P002:667; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This view of the 155mm heavy artillery piece. Of special note the gun still shows the remnants of the WWI style camouflage (3 color type) used on equipment in the WWI through early 1920s period. The huge bore of the heavy gun is featured as well as the hard rubber wheels on the carriage. Photo is taken inside of the Armory building showing the construction of the huge open parade/training area.
  - OAC Military Tournament/Inspection Day - Pre 1925, circa 1920
    This sub series of photographs includes OAC Cadet formations on Inspection Day. An annual event on the OAC Campus, Military Review or "Inspection Day" involved the entire cadet division. Representatives from the Military Department would attend the ceremonies and certify the ROTC Program and its personnel. OAC Boasted a continuous Excellent rating in these evaluations for most of the 1920s and 30s. Uniforms of cadets and officers date to Pre 1925 uniform regulations. Officers jackets have the high collar (vintage WWI) design which was changed in 1925. Many of the photos in the sub series portray marching formations of cadets on the parade field below Benton Hall.
    - Military review spectators passing Armory, circa 1920; P002:580; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Spectators arriving to view military day at OAC, Armory in background. Jefferson Street with auto traffic on left.
    - Cadets walking in line by Armory, circa 1920; P002:583; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s.
    - Company of cadets marching, circa 1920; P002:591; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Cadet company marching on lower campus parade field.
    - Group of cadets seated on grass with speaker, circa 1920; P002:593; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Speaker addressing (possibly General McAlexander) large group of cadets on lower campus below Benton Hall. Band members also seated on grass with group.
    - Charging cadet formation, military demonstration, circa 1920; P002:594; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadets demonstrating a bayonet charge.
    - Inspection formation with cadets at attention, circa 1920; P002:595; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Lines of cadets at attention waiting for inspection.
    - Cadet formations on lower campus, inspection day, circa 1920; P002:596; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Wide view of parade field with cadet formations. Benton Hall in background.
    - Bayonet demonstration cadet formation, circa 1920; P002:597; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadets with fixed bayonets in demonstration probably on inspection day
    - Mc Alexander Field House (Armory) with cadet formations, circa 1920; P002:598; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Cadet formations marching by Armory.
    - Group of cadets sitting on grass with speaker, circa 1920; P002:600; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Large group of cadets on grass listening to speaker at left. Unidentified speaker in uniform, possibly McAlexander? Officers are being group standing, at right.
    - Cadets marching past Mc Alexander Field House (Armory), circa 1920; P002:601; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet formations marching past Armory. Jefferson Street on left with columns of cadets marching on sidewalks.
    - Campus view Bandstand and Pharmacy Building, circa 1920; P002:602; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Campus view showing quad area with bandstand at right. Pharmacy bldg and Benton Hall in background. Photograph is probably vintage 1920s and appears not to show any military formations or cadets.
    - McAlexander Field house (Armory Bldg) with Cadet formations, circa 1920; P002:603; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Good view of the Mc Alexander Field House (then Armory) with cadets marching in parade field adjacent to Jefferson Street.
    - Cadet formations marching past reviewing spectators with packs, circa 1920; P002:605; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Cadets marching in formation with field packs. Spectator gallery in view with some small children in group.
    - Cadets marching onto parade field, circa 1920; P002:606; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Company formations of cadets marching on parade field. This photo shows cadets with full field packs, a rare photo in the series.
    - Military Department representatives reviewing cadets, circa 1920; P002:607; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Poorly focused photo of cadets passing in review. Military Department representatives and possibly President Kerr viewing marching cadets.
    - Cadets marching in columns, inspection day, circa 1920; P002:608; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Cadet formation of companies marching in column style.
    - Rear view, cadets marching in line, circa 1920; P002:609; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. cadets marching in single file line, away from camera. Uniforms show the leather cartridge case on belts.
    - Right Shoulder Arms, Forward March, circa 1920; P002:610; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Right shoulder arms, forward march.
    - Company D, infantry cadets flag on parade field, circa 1920; P002:611; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Cadet Infantry Company D flag on parade field.
    - Cadets on parade field, inspection day, circa 1920; P002:612; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide, high angle shot of cadets on parade field, inspection day
    - Graduation day cadet formations aerial view, circa 1920; P002:614; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Graduation day high level photograph of parade field. View shows spectators in long dresses and suits. Graduating class, in caps and gowns are lined up on left hand side of field.
    - Graduation day cadet formations aerial view #2, circa 1920; P002:615; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. This was an annual event in the OAC year which included a review of the cadets by college and military dignitaries, parades and military demonstrations. High angle photograph, almost aerial view of parade field with cadet formations. Detail examination shows groups of cadets in graduation cap and gowns in front of their respective companies.
    - Cadet formations ready for inspection wide shot, circa 1920; P002:616; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A grouping of period photographs of OAC Cadet corps in various formations probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. This was an annual event in the OAC year which included a review of the cadets by college and military dignitaries, parades and military demonstrations. Formations of cadet companies in many of this grouping are shown on the lower campus with the Education Building (Science Bldg) and the old Gymnasium in background.
    - Cadet formation ready for inspection, circa 1920; P002:617; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. This was an annual event in the OAC year which included a review of the cadets by college and military dignitaries, parades and military demonstrations. Formation of cadets ready for inspection.
    - Cadet formation with stretcher squad, circa 1920; P002:618; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Company formations of cadets at parade rest. Squad of stretcher bearers at right. Cadet officer leaning on his sabre.
    - Marching cadets with rifles, circa 1920; P002:619; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. This was an annual event in the OAC year which included a review of the cadets by college and military dignitaries, parades and military demonstrations. Rifles on shoulders are still probably the Pre WWI Krag Jorgensen .30 Caliber.
    - Cadet formation with band, circa 1920; P002:620; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Cadet formation including OAC Cadet Band at left.
    - Cadets marching on field by Armory, circa 1920; P002:630; 2.0 3 x 5 prints (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Formation of cadets marching in background with Mc Alexander field house (Armory) on right.
    - Cadets walking on lower campus in formation, circa 1920; P002:633; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Small group of cadets walking in formation (informally) with rifles.
    - Movement of cadet formation on parade field, circa 1920; P002:634; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Two cadet companies marching on parade field with rifles.
    - Cadet Company marching on parade field, circa 1920; P002:635; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet company marching on parade field, inspection day
    - Inspection Day formations wide view, circa 1920; P002:636; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Overall view of cadet formations on lower campus, probably inspection day
    - Cadet formation marching on lower campus, circa 1920; P002:637; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Company formation marching on lower campus
    - View of parade field with cadet formations, circa 1920; P002:641; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide view of parade field with all cadet companies in formation for inspection day
    - View of parade field with cadet formations #2, circa 1920; P002:642; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide view of cadet formations on parade field ready for inspection day
    - Company of cadets marching, circa 1920; P002:643; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet company marching in formation to inspection day parade field
    - OAC Cadet Band marching with instruments, circa 1920; P002:644; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      OAC Cadet band marching with instruments at inspection day
    - Cadets informally marching lower campus, circa 1920; P002:645; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Informal group of cadets marching back home from inspection day. Some with rifles on shoulders, some at sides, group is organized but not formally marching.
    - Officer addressing group of cadets, circa 1920; P002:646; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Officer talking with company of cadets. Rifles are of the newer 1903 Springfield type, replacing the Pre Spanish American War Krag-Jorgensen rifles seen issued to cadets in the 1900-1918 period.
    - Cadets waiting for their turn to be inspected, circa 1920; P002:647; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet formation waiting for their turn to be inspected by Military Department representatives
    - Line abreast formation moving on parade field, circa 1920; P002:648; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet company moving in line abreast formation on parade field
    - Close order drill formation for inspection day, circa 1920; P002:649; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet company marching on parade field in close order drill, inspection day
    - Company formation marching lower campus, circa 1920; P002:650; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet company marching in formation on lower campus
    - Double Time! March!, circa 1920; P002:651; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Column of cadets moving at double time in formation probably on inspection day
    - Parade field with cadet formations, circa 1920; P002:652; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide view of cadet formations on inspection day. Of note is the company on left wearing the WWI era "body armor" vests.
    - Troops marching past Armory, circa 1920; P002:653; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet formations moving past the Armory
    - Company formation of cadets at rest by Armory, circa 1920; P002:666; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      With the Armory (Mc Alexander Field House) in background, the formation of cadets are grouped with officers speaking. Flags and company colors are at rear of formation, this indicates that the group could possibly be forming up for inspection day activities.
    - Cadet formation viewed from rear, circa 1920; P002:667; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A view of the cadet formation from the rear showing them marching toward the Armory. Photograph is similar to many in this grouping of marching cadets on lower campus parade field. Formations are being moved into position for inspection day activities, circa 1920.
    - Column of cadets marching past Pharmacy Building, circa 1920; P002:670; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet formation marching past the Pharmacy Building with Benton Hall in the background. College coed dressed in exercise outfit (?) watching them pass.
    - Wide view of cadet formations, Inspection day, circa 1920; P002:672; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide angle view of cadet regiment marching in formation on parade field.
    - Cadet formation on parade field, circa 1920; P002:673; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Movement of cadets on lower campus, probably inspection day
    - Cadet formation marching on parade field, c1920, circa 1920; P002:676; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photograph is similar to many in this grouping of marching cadets on lower campus parade field. Formations are being moved into position for inspection day activities, circa 1920.
    - Detail of speaker to cadet formation, possibly Gen. Mc Alexander, circa 1920; P002:674; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This detail photo is related to P002:593 and 600 showing the speaker they are listening to. The profile of the subject could be General McAlexander. While in a uniform, there is no rank insignia shown. The individual is wearing a garrison cap with plaid markings, not seen on any other cadets of the period.
    - Group of cadets next to Old Gymnasium, circa 1920; P002:675; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This group of cadets are informally gathering in the lower area by the Old Gymnasium. The gymnasium later became the College Playhouse and Mitchell Playhouse. Today it is the Gladys Valley Gymnastics Center.
    - Company of cadets moving forward into formation, circa 1920; P002:678; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
    - Company of cadets moving into formation, circa 1920; P002:679; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. Formations are being moved into position for inspection day activities, circa 1920.
    - Company formations waiting for inspection, circa 1920; P002:680; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
    - Spectator crowd observing inspection day, circa 1920; P002:685; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This photograph is poorly focused, but appears to be the crowd of spectators for the formations of cadets marching on the parade field. Agriculture Hall in background.
    - Spectators observing cadet formation on parade field, circa 1920; P002:686; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Small group of spectators watching movement of cadet company on parade field, lower campus across from Education Building.
    - Cadet regiment marching to parade field, behind Education Building, circa 1920; P002:687; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      A photograph of OAC Cadet corps in formation probably on "Inspection Day" early 1920s. View from above, of entire cadet regiment moving onto the lower campus parade field. Education Building (Science Hall) rear of building is on left.
    - Cadet Regiment marching onto parade field #2, circa 1920; P002:688; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Similar view to P002:687, this photograph includes color guard marching in formation. Entire cadet regiment moving onto parade field, lower campus.
    - Spectator crowd observing inspection day, circa 1920; P002:689; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This photograph is better focused,and appears to be the crowd of spectators for the formations of cadets marching on the parade field. Agriculture Hall in background.
    - Officers with man and woman inspection day, circa 1920; P002:690; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)